Grand Rapids, MI. South Congregational Church records, 1850-2001.
Congregational Library & Archives
Grand Rapids, MI. South Congregational Church records, 1850-2001.
RG4657
Congregational Library & Archives
6.02 Cubic Feet
(7 boxes, 214 items)
The origins of South Congregational Church start in 1874 when women from the Park Avenue Congregational Church organized a Sunday School. This would eventually lead to a "Mr. Gilbert" donating land for construction of a chapel. The new chapel was located between Sheldon and Jefferson on Delaware Street and finished in 1876. The South Congregational Church was officially organized on December 12, 1878 with 43 charter members. The church would see steady growth until the end of the 1900s, when membership began to decline and financial resources became stretched. The community decided to close in 2001 and held its final service on September 9th. This collection contains church records such as vital statistics and meeting minutes, historical records such as anniversaries and newspaper articles, financial records such as account books and mortgages, organizational records for groups like the Ladies Aid Society and Missionary Society, and pastoral records like sermons and correspondences.
South Congregational Church (Grand Rapids, Mich.)
Collins, Earl
Cotton, William
Reikow, Philip E.
Skidmore, Ronald C.
Child, Virginia H.
Restrictions on Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Acquisition Information
Materials were donated to the Congregational Library by Virginia Child in September 2001; 2001-04.
Historical Note
The origins of South Congregational Church start in 1874 when women from the Park Avenue Congregational Church organized a Sunday School. This would eventually lead to a "Mr. Gilbert" donating land for construction of a chapel. The new chapel was located between Sheldon and Jefferson on Delaware Street and finished in 1876. The South Congregational Church was officially organized on December 12, 1878 with 43 charter members. The group was accepted into the Grand River Conference the following year. Also in 1879, the minister Rev. Sarjent oversaw the expansion of the building due to growth of membership. The building was moved in 1886 to the cordner of Delaware and Sheldon, accompanied by additional expansion. Four separate ministers took the pulpit in the 1890s including Rev. Frederick York in 1896. The following year, the church suffered a fire which nearly destroyed everything. Funds were raised to not only repair but expand as the membership had seen continual growth.
Multiple ministers would take over during the early 1900s with the longest tenured being Rev. Charles Grieshaber who served from 1909-1926. The church was hit by a fire again, this time during building repairs in 1936. When Rev. Earl Collins took over in 1941, he oversaw another large increase in membership. This increase led the community to seek a new home in the growing south part of the city. The church moved to the corner of Madison and Alger and included a social hall, offices and classrooms. At this time, the number of people in the Sunday School was nearly 800. The church would continue at this new location with numerous other pastors until a tornado struck on April 21, 1967. A building fund was launched shortly after and a brand new Sanctuary was dedicated two years later in February 1969. The church mortgage was completely paid off in 1970. At this time, the church was still fully committed to education, having around 450 students.
The church membership began to decline and financial resources became stretched. The community decided to close in 2001 and held its final service on September 9th. At the final dedication, the church noted all the different ways they would provide resources after disbanding. This included selling the building to the New Covenant Life Ministries, while donating other items to Remember, Burton Heights Elementary School, and to the Interfaith Hospitality Network. Proceeds of the sale were given to the Pilgrim Manor Foundation, United Church Outreach Ministries, Habitat for Humanity, and finally a trust given to the Michigan Conference UCC for a Southside Grand Rapids New Church Start.
Ministers
Rev. Mr. Brown 1876
Rev. Eugene C. Olney 1877-1879
Rev. Benjamin F. Sargent 1880-1889
Dr. Franklin Noble 1889-1891
Rev. James E. Smith 1891-1894
Rev. Gainor P. Moore 1894-1896
Rev. Frederick E. York 1896-1904
Rev. John Gordon 1904-1908
Rev. Charles O. Grieshaber 1909-1926
Rev. William A. Minty 1926-1931
Rev. Harold M. Skidmore 1931-1941
Rev. Earl F. Collins 1941-1951
Rev. Charles W. Scheid 1951-1966
Rev. W. R. Catton (Interim) 1966
Rev. Richard L. Ford 1966-1976
R. H. McConnell (Interim) 1977
Rev. Philip E. Reikow 1977-1989
Rev. Ronald C. Skidmore 1989-1998
Rev. H. A. Martling (Interim) 1998-1999
Rev. Dr. Virginia H. Child 1999-2001
Scope and Contents
This collection contains church records such as vital statistics and meeting minutes, historical records such as anniversaries and newspaper articles, financial records such as account books and mortgages, organizational records for groups like the Ladies Aid Society and Missionary Society, and pastoral records like sermons and correspondences.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged into five series and four sub-series. The records in each series has been arranged chronologically by start date except in the meetings and reports sub-series.
Series 1: Church records, 1850-2001
Subseries 1: Vital statistics, 1850-2000
Subseries 2: Meetings and reports, 1899-2001
Subseries 3: Newsletters, 1922-2001
Subseries 4: Visual materials, 1978-1996, undated
Series 2: Historical records, 1880-2001
Series 3: Financial, 1891-2001
Series 4: Pastoral, 1896-2000
Series 5: Organizations, 1905-1935, 1966-2001
Technical Requirements
The collection contains VHS tapes and a reel which the library does not have the equipment to properly play.
Bibliography
1. Historian's reports and sketches, in the Grand Rapids, MI. South Congregational Church records, 1850-2001, RG4657. The Congregational Library & Archives, Boston, MA.
2. Closing service of worship, in the Grand Rapids, MI. South Congregational Church records, 1850-2001, RG4657. The Congregational Library & Archives, Boston, MA.
Church records and registers.; Vital statistics.; Installation (clergy).; Church finance.; Photographs.; Letters.; Church newsletters.; Christian stewardship.; Church societies.; Sermons.; Church buildings; South Congregational Church (Grand Rapids, Mich.)
- Church records, 1850 2001; 1850-2001; 118 Items; (1 reel, 6 tapes, 111 folders)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains church records from the South Congregational Church and includes vital statistics, meeting minutes, various church reports, newsletters and visual materials.
  - Vital statistics, 1850 2000; 1850-2000; 20 Folders
    This subseries contains the vital statistics from the South Congregational Church and includes membership lists, transfers, dismissals, marriages, baptisms, directories and a membership survey.
    - Vital statistics and meeting minutes, 1850 1923; 1850-1923 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Membership records, 1878 2000; 1878-2000 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Membership list, 1889 1978; 1889-1978 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Removed members list, 1889 1978; 1889-1978 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Membership list, 1880 1943; 1880-1943 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Transfers and Dismissals, 1891 1924; 1891-1924 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Jesse Fry's handbook of records, 1893 1930; 1893-1930 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Jesse Fry's handbook of records, 1898 1932; 1898-1932 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Jesse Fry's handbook of records, 1899 1927; 1899-1927 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Jesse Fry's handbook of records (1 of 2), 1903 1933; 1903-1933 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Jesse Fry's handbook of records (2 of 2), 1903 1933; 1903-1933 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Records of weddings and funerals, 1906 1967; 1906-1967 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Baptism list, 1922 2000; 1922-2000 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Marriage records, 1931 1989; 1931-1989 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Baptismal records, 1965 1983; 1965-1983 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Directories, 1968 1978; 1968-1978 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Directories, 1984 1994; 1984-1994 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Inactive member survey, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Marriage services, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Membership index file, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Meetings and reports, 1899 2001; 1899-2001; 55 Folders
    This subseries contains meetings and reports related to the South Congregational Church. This includes the Board of Trustees, Annual reports, meeting minutes, Church council meeting minutes, and yearbook reports.
    Arrangement
    This subseries is arranged chronologically by group, with one-offs at the end.
    - Board of Trustees meeting minutes, 1899 1907; 1899-1907 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Board of Trustees meeting minutes, 1907 1922; 1907-1922 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Board of Trustees meeting minutes, 1923 1934; 1923-1934 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Board of Trustees meeting minutes, 1934 1943; 1934-1943 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Board of Trustees meeting minutes, 1973-02 1977-08; February 1973-August 1977 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Board of Trustees meeting minutes, 1977-09 1980-06; September 1977-June 1980 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Board of Trustees meeting minutes, 1981-01 1982-12; January 1981-December 1982 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Board of Trustees meeting minutes, 1983 1986; 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Board of Trustees notes and correspondences, 1984 1990; 1984-1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Board of Trustees meeting minutes, 1987-01 1989-05; January 1987-May 1989 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Board of Trustees booklet, 1988 1992; 1988-1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Board of Trustees meeting minutes, 1989-06 1991-12; June 1989-December 1991 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Board of Trustees meeting minutes, 1992 1993; 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Board of Trustees meeting minutes, 1994 1997; 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Annual reports, 1900 1920; 1900-1920 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Annual reports, 1922 1930; 1922-1930 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Annual reports, 1931 1938; 1931-1938 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Annual reports, 1939 1945; 1939-1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Annual reports, 1946 1949; 1946-1949 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Annual reports, 1950 1954; 1950-1954 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Annual reports, 1955 1956; 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Annual reports, 1958 1959; 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Annual reports, 1960 1962; 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Annual reports, 1963 1966; 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Annual reports, 1967 1968; 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Annual reports, 1970 1971; 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Annual reports, 1972 1975; 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Annual reports, 1976 1978; 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Annual reports, 1979 1981; 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Annual reports, 1982 1984; 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Annual reports, 1985 1987; 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Annual reports, 1988 1991; 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Annual reports, 1992 1995; 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Annual reports, 1996 1999; 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Annual reports, 2000 2001; 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Meeting minutes, 1930 1931; 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Meeting minutes, 1941 1961; 1941-1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Meeting minutes, 1961 1962; 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Meeting minutes, 1963 1967; 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Meeting minutes, 1967 1978; 1967-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Meeting minutes, 1978 1994; 1978-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Meeting minutes, 1995 2001; 1995-2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Church council meeting minutes, 1951 1968; 1951-1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Church council meeting minutes, 1969 1982; 1969-1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Church council meeting minutes, 1983 1989; 1983-1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Church council meeting minutes, 1990 1992; 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Church council meeting minutes, 1992 1993-10; 1992-October 1993 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Church council meeting minutes, 1993-11 1996; November 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Church council meeting minutes, 1997 1998-01; 1997-January 1998 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Congregational yearbook reports, 1910 1930; 1910-1930 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Congregational yearbook reports, 1966 2000; 1966-2000 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Church records and reports, 1877 1941; 1877-1941 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Church reports, 1924 1926; 1924-1926 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Refugee family records, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Board and committee reports and notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Newsletters, 1922 2001; 1922-2001; 27 Folders
    This subseries contains newsletters produced by the South Congregational Church and includes the South Church Messenger, The Fountain Pen, South Church Page, and The Messenger.
    - South Church Messenger, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - The Fountain Pen, 1931-04 1931-06; April-June 1931 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - South Church Page, 1931-09 1931-12; September-December 1931 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - South Church Page, 1932-01 1932-11; January-November 1932 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - South Church Page, 1932-12 1933-12; December 1932-December 1933 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - South Church Page, 1934-01 1935-02; January 1934-February 1935 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - South Church Page, 1935-03 1935-12; March-December 1935 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - South Church Page, 1936-01 1936-06; January-June 1936 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - South Church Page, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - South Church Messenger, 1968 1971; 1968-1971 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - South Church Messenger, 1972-12 1974-04; December 1972-April 1974 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - South Church Messenger, 1974-05 1978-01; May 1974-January 1978 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - The Messenger, 1978-02 1978-12; February-December 1978 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - The Messenger, 1979 1980; 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - The Messenger, 1981 1982-07; 1981-July 1982 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - The Messenger, 1982-09 1983-11; September 1982-November 1983 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - The Messenger, 1984 1988-02; 1984-February 1988 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - South Church Messenger, 1988-02 1989-09; February 1988-September 1989 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - South Church Messenger, 1989-09 1990-12; October 1989-December 1990 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - South Church Messenger, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - South Church Messenger, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - South Church Messenger, 1993 1994; 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - South Church Messenger, 1995-01 1995-09; January-August 1995 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - The Messenger, 1995-09 1997-12; September 1995-1997 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - The Messenger, 1998 1999; 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - The Messenger, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - The Messenger, 2001-01 2001-09; January-August 2001 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Visual materials, 1978 1996; 1978-1996, undated; 16 Items; (1 reel, 6 tapes, 9 folders)
    This subseries contains visual materials from the church and includes photos, VHS tapes of church events and a rededication service on a reel.
    - Centennial Sunday rededication service, October 27, 1978 (Box 6, Reel 1)
    - Jonah, 1992 (Box 6, Tape 1)
    - Children's Cantata-Elijah, Man of Fire, April 17, 1994 (Box 6, Tape 5)
    - Adam's Apple children, 1995-05-17 (Box 6, Tape 4)
    - Church Activities, April 2, 1996 (Box 6, Tape 3)
    - Photos (1 of 5), undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Photos (2 of 5), undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Photos (3 of 5), undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Photos (4 of 5), undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Photos (5 of 5), undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Church slides, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Planting the Seeds of our Faith (copy 1), undated (Box 6, Tape 2)
    - Planting the Seeds of our Faith (copy 2), undated (Box 6, Tape 6)
    - Do Things Right class pins, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Oversize Images (1 of 2), undated (Drawer 11, Folder 6)
    - Oversize Images (2 of 2), undated (Drawer 11, Folder 7)
- Historical records, 1880 2001; 1880-2001; 27 Folders
  This series contains historical records related to the church and includes anniversaries, pamphlets, newspaper articles, order of services and constitutions.
  - Does it play to support the gospel here?, October 24, 1880 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Church pamphlets and manuals, 1884 1923; 1884-1923 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Constitution with amendments, 1895 1940; 1895-1912, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - 25th Anniversary, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Order of services, 1904 1931; 1904-1931 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Resolutions, 1912 1920; 1912-1920 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Michigan Congregational Conference appointment, 1912 1922; 1912-1922 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Newspaper articles, 1916 1972; 1916-1972 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - 50th Anniversary, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Ye Olde Singing Skule, 1933-02-28 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Historical Sketches, 1944 1949; 1944-1949 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - 70th Anniversary, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Cornerstone time capsule, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Historian's reports and sketches, 1950 1994; 1950-1994 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - 75th Anniversary, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Order of services, 1962 1975; 1962-1975 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Certificate, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - 90th Anniversary, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Church dedication services, 1968 1970; 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Sharing the good news, 1975 1976; 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Order of services, 1977 1991; 1977-1991 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - 100th Anniversary, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Constitution, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Certificates, 1991 2000; 1991-2000 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Order of services, 1992 2000; 1992-2000 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Constitution, 1999 2001; 1999-2001 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Closing service of worship, September 9, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Financial, 1891 2001; 1891-2001; 39 Folders
  This series contains financial records from the church and includes account books, indentures, building records, mortgages, treasurer's reports, non-profit paperwork, deeds and information on selling property.
  - Indentures, 1891 1950; 1891-1950 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Financial reports, 1894 1919; 1894-1919 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Account book, 1899 1902; 1899-1902 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Financial statements, 1899 1919; 1899-1919 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Treasurer's book, 1909 1929; 1909-1929 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Tax history, 1919 1942; 1919-1942 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Real estate records, 1919 1974; 1919-1974 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Articles of incorporation, 1922 1925; 1922-1925 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Treasurer's book, 1922 1952; 1922-1952 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Account book, 1923 1924; 1923-1924 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Grand Rapids Association, 1924 1930; 1924, 1928-1930 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Christian endeavor society reports, 1926 1929; 1926-1929 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Account book, 1927 1929; 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Treasurer's reports, 1928 1935; 1928-1935 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Proposal plans for the enlargement and improvement of First Congregational Church, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Account book, 1929 1935; 1929-1935 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Bequests, 1931 1998; 1931-1998 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Indenture of Mortgage, 1935 1945; 1935, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Mortgages, 1935 1976; 1935-1976 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Abstract of title, October 29, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Treasurer's reports, 1942 1943; 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Articles of incorporation, 1943 1947; 1943-1947 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Buliding committee meeting minutes, 1943 1949; 1943-1949 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Church building fund reports, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Barnes construction and sanctuary, 1949 1950; 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Michigan non-profit paperwork, 1949 1978; 1949-1978 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Subordination Agreement, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Abstract of title, 1951-05-24 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Subordination agreement, July 6, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Pilgrim Manor records, 1957 1964; 1957-1964 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Construction and dedication of new sanctuary, 1967 1971; 1967-1971 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Friendship Sunday survey, October 6, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Board for world service, 1980 1983; 1980-1983 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - New Life Covenant Ministries tenant records, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Warranty Deed, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Appraisal of sanctuary, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Sale of church property, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Mortgage, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Building Fund bonds, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Pastoral, 1896 2000; 1896-2000; 13 Folders
  This series contains records related to the pastors of the church and includes reports, messages, correspondences, sermons, and installations.
  - Church correspondences, 1896 1903; 1896-1903 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Church correspondences, 1907 1931; 1907-1931 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Pastor reports and messages, 1913 1931; 1913-1931 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Pastor reports and messages, 1925 1926; 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Rev. Earl Collins correspondences, 1948 1951; 1948-1951 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Rev. William Cotton biographies, 1958 1964; 1958-1964 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Condolence on death of Rev. Earl Collins, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Sermons, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Pastoral notes and records, 1972 1975; 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Installation of Rev. Philip E. Reikow, October 23, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Installation of Rev. Ronald C. Skidmore, 1989-10-29 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Pastoral notes and records, 1998 1999; 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Installation of Rev. Dr. Virginia H. Child, March 19, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Organizations, 1905 2001; 1905-1935, 1966-2001; 17 Folders
  This series contains records related to the various organizations of South Congregational Church and includes the Home society, Missionary society, Ladies Aid Society, Women's Fellowship, service team, nomination committee, Top of the Hill club, Diaconate, and Vision team.
  - Home and Missionary Society reports, 1905 1922; 1905-1922 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Missionary Society meeting minutes, 1922 1930; 1922-1930 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Ladies Aid Society minute book, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Ladies Aid Society meeting minutes, 1931 1932; 1931-1932 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Missionary Society meeting minutes, 1931 1935; 1931-1935 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Rules and By-laws of the Women's Fellowship, 1966 1971; 1966-1971 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Top of the Hill club records, 1975 1978; 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Diaconate meeting records, 1977 1980; 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Women's Fellowship records, 1981 1991; 1981-1991 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Diaconate meeting records, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Diaconate meeting records, 1982 1985; 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Nomination committee records, 1987 1996; 1987-1996 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Diaconate meeting records, 1990 1997; 1990-1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Vision team meeting minutes, 1992 1995; 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Vision team plans and notes, 1997 2001; 1997-2001 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Service team records, 1998 2000; 1998-2000 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Vision team meeting minutes, 1998 2001; 1998-2001 (Box 2, Folder 16)